Forced mate! Mate!
Nice move this round.
You're trading cannons, huh?
Yeah. It's time to trade.
Gentlemen.
Can I ask you something?
How do I get to Xia Gang's place?
The one from the shipyard.
Go all the way in and then turn right.
First one on the left.
Why are you looking for Xia?
Bring out the rook.
Check.
[THE GUILTY]
[Episode 5]
[Flower Shop]
[Waiting for you in the forest at Lover's Peak at 9 p.m.]
Lu Ming.
[Flower Shop]
Where's Lu Ming?
I knocked, but he wasn't home.
Have you seen him?
I haven't seen him either.
[Tomb of Xia Gang, a loving father]
What happened to the tombstone?
Who did this?
It's messed up.
[Tomb of Xia Gang, a loving father]
Xia Xue!
I know it's you.
Stop hiding.
Xia Xue.
Stop hiding. Come out!
Stop!
Lu Ming!
Stop hitting me!
Or I'll call the police!
I know you killed Ma Ke.
I have the videotape.
[Tomb of Xia Gang, a loving father]
Xia,
everything's fine.
Don't worry.
Let's go.
Let's wait a bit longer.
Lu Ming hasn't come yet.
He's not that unreliable.
Something urgent must have come up.
I'll get someone to fix this tomorrow.
Can it be fixed?
Yes, it can.
Where have you been?
Why are you only here now?
I overslept.
Don't you know what day it is?
And you overslept?
Unbelievable.
You overslept?
Hurry up and offer incense to Xia.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
[Tomb of Xia Gang, a loving father]
Let's go.
When are you going back to Huacheng?
I'll wait a bit longer.
What are you waiting for?
I still have some things to take care of.
What things?
My personal business.
Stay out of it.
Move!
Kill me if you have the guts.
Tomorrow, someone will take the tape
to the police.
And all three of you will die.
What do you want?
If I give the tape to Ma Derong,
how much do you think he'd pay me?
How much do you want?
It's simple.
Two hundred thousand.
In exchange for the lives
of the three of you.
I don't have money.
Three lives, for heaven's sake!
[Enforcement Bureau
of the Nanping City People’s Court]
Chen Hu.
Do you have any legal document
writing jobs?
What's wrong, Lu Ming?
Nothing.
Go ask at the entrance of Nanping Court.
It seems like
lots of people there need legal advice.
Hello, do you need documents drafted?
[Law student's legal consultation
and document drafting services]
No, no.
Do you need documents drafted?
[People's Procuratorate of Nanping City]
Hello. Legal advice, document drafting?
No.
Hello.
Here's my card.
Brother.
I majored in law in college.
I'll definitely be cheaper than them.
Drafting documents,
legal advice, I can do it all.
The foreman won't pay.
Can you get the money back?
You'll have to give me the details.
I have a cousin
who works as a diver
at a construction site.
A few days ago, he went into
a foundation pit to retrieve a drill bit.
They had a deal.
If he goes down and comes up,
he gets 10,000.
If he goes down and doesn't come back up,
he gets a million.
In the end, he died in the pit.
How much?
A million.
I mean, if he came back up.
Ten thousand.
Who's qualified to do this job?
Good swimmers who aren't afraid of death.
Coming.
Xue.
Auntie.
Is Lu Ming home?
He's not with you?
He went out early this morning.
Did he go looking for Lin Hua?
Well, I-I-I'll get going then.
Why are you looking for him?
Nothing. I just...
got bored staying home alone,
so I thought I'd ask him to take a walk.
Go back inside and wait.
I'll go find him right now!
Wait here.
No need, Auntie.
I'll just walk around by myself.
Bye.
[Everlasting Bloom Florist]
[Death Certificate]
He's not that unreliable.
Something urgent must have come up.
Any divers?
What is it?
Anyone?
Can't do it.
Too dangerous.
Anyone?
Me.
You look like a boiled chicken.
Have you done this before?
I have.
The drill bit broke in the pit.
Are you doing it or not?
How much if I come back up?
How much if I don't?
If you come up, 6,000.
If you don't, 800,000.
I want 20,000 if I come up.
Are you out of your mind?
Anyone else want the job?
Two hundred thousand in exchange
for the lives of three of you.
Three lives, for heaven's sake!
If I don't come up, I only want 200,000.
You said it.
Come, let's get the gear.
Kid, it's not too late to back out now.
Pay up! Pay up!
Calm down, everyone.
We're finding solutions for you.
We told you long ago.
Don't put hydrogen tanks near the welding.
You didn't listen.
The wiring got old.
No one replaced it.
Of course something went wrong.
These were your responsibilities!
You have to compensate our losses!
It's because he was always trying to
cut corners at the factory.
Expired fire extinguishers
weren't replaced,
which delayed firefighting efforts
after the explosion.
These were his responsibilities.
They have nothing to do with me!
Come, come.
Qiu.
Xia Xue.
You're finally here.
Qiu, what's wrong?
Well...
This accident
has a lot to do with your dad.
Your father died
in the shipyard explosion.
He left me with this mess.
What do you think we should do?
My dad?
Girl.
This was your dad's mistake.
You have to take responsibility for him.
Auntie, it has nothing to do with my dad.
Didn't you hear the manager?
The explosion happened because of issues
your dad was responsible for!
-Exactly.
-It’s all because of your dad!
The oxygen is running out.
Why isn't he up yet?
Pull.
Pull!
It's stuck, it won't move!
Lu Ming, stop sleeping. Wake up.
Stop sleeping! Wake up.
Are you a pig? Still sleeping?
Lu Ming!
Hurry, pull.
Hurry. One, two, three.
You've got some serious luck.
You didn't move for so long.
I thought you were a goner.
I can't die.
Everyone, calm down.
Let's talk this out. What's going on?
Lin Hua,
stop making trouble here.
You're not Lu Ming.
Why are you protecting her?
Yeah.
Why, are you guys dating?
Watch how you talk.
This has nothing to do with us either.
We are victims too.
Girl, just tell us
if you're paying up or not.
If you're not, we'll call the police.
Call the police!
If you guys call the police,
it has nothing to do with us.
It's not our problem.
What does it have to do with us?
We'll call the police!
Stop this. Stop!
Who are you?
Who I am doesn't matter.
So many of you
ganging up on a kid.
Don't you feel ashamed?
Who we hassle is none of your business.
-Are you okay?
-If you love meddling so much,
why don't you pay up instead?
Exactly!
Who asked you to speak?
I'm Mr. Ma's secretary.
You should say less.
Yeah, let's go.
Stop talking.
Coming through.
Make way.
Compensation for the deceased,
medical costs for the injured,
and severance pay for laid-off workers.
Mr. Ma has arranged everything.
I can guarantee
that every single one of you
will get the money you deserve.
If you keep surrounding this place
and causing trouble,
I'll have to report to Mr. Ma
that you don't want a solution,
and just want to cause a scene!
We do want a solution.
If you want a solution,
then please wait patiently, okay?
Think it through.
All your problems can be solved!
Is what you said true?
Rest assured.
I keep my word.
If this isn't resolved, come find me!
Okay?
Don't crowd here anymore.
Go home for now.
Wait for news. It'll be solved soon.
Let's go. Break it up.
Wait.
Take this.
Regarding your father's unpaid wages,
I will process them as soon as possible.
If you have any trouble,
my number is on there. Just call me.
Don't listen to their nonsense.
Xia definitely had nothing
to do with the explosion.
It's all Qiu's fault.
Please don't take it to heart.
Why did you come alone?
Where is Lu Ming?
I went to his house to look for him.
He...
He wasn't home.
Not home?
Go to work first.
I'm going home.
Here's ten thousand for now.
I'm still earning the rest.
No, Lu Ming, are you kidding me?
Do you think you're paying off
a bank loan?
How about this?
I'll write you an IOU.
You're a murderer.
Talking to me about credit?
Write an IOU?
Do you think you can write
an IOU for everything?
Xia Gang's compensation
will be dispensed soon.
Maybe I'll ask Xia Xue!
This is my business.
Big, big, place your bets.
Small, small, small!
Big, big, big!
I won!
Bets are locked.
Please place your bets in order.
Touch me again and see what happens.
See if I won't
expose your secret.
If you get locked up,
what will happen to Xia Xue?
You'd let that cripple take care of her?
When will you pay the rest?
One month.
Five days.
If I don't get the money in five days,
I'll go straight to Ma Derong.
How did I lose again?
I've lost all my savings.
Big, big, big!
Got a light?
No.
I realise you're pretty interesting.
I've been watching you all night.
You've been wandering around,
looking everywhere but never betting.
Are you scared
or are your pockets empty?
In Nanping, if you need money,
I'm the one to see.
[Fu Wenchang, Sancheng Financial Services]
They call me Chang.
Call me if you need anything.
How much can I borrow?
Chang.
Look, I'm about to...
180,000?
So much?
[Sancheng Finance]
Are you a student?
How much did you lose?
You're trying to win it back?
I don't gamble.
And I don't know how to.
I don't.
You don't gamble or smoke.
So you're just watching
the pretty dealers deal?
Chang.
How many times have I told you?
Be polite to customers.
Look, you're borrowing so much money.
You don't gamble or smoke.
What do you need it for?
I have my own reasons.
Nine out, thirteen back.
He already explained it to me.
I understand that.
Borrowing money is easy.
I can give it to you right away.
So, let's-
How many times have I said it?
Be polite to customers!
Let's calculate it
and write an IOU first.
This way.
Chang.
Make tea.
About the explosion case,
the police are still investigating.
As a family member of a victim,
we hope you will find peace
and cooperate with us
to comfort the families
of the deceased shipyard workers.
You've seen the car.
You heard what Li Dong said.
It's not me saying
that my son didn't die at the scene.
The witnesses and evidence are all there.
Although I...
signed the death certificate,
if there is a one in ten thousand chance,
I must find my son.
I must.
Let go. Hands off!
Move!
Let go!
Nobody move!
Lu Ming.
Here to deliver the money?
You didn't rob a bank, did you?
Where is the tape?
What's the rush?
I'll go get it for you right now.
It's brilliant.
Look.
Look at what you've done.
You guys are really something.
Give it to me.
If a third person finds out,
even if I die,
I'll drag you down with me.
Okay.
Lu Ming.
Lu Ming!
How did this happen?
Come on, I'll take you to the hospital.
Let's go.
I'm fine.
Lu Ming.
What have you been doing lately?
Nothing.
Okay.
You won't tell the truth, will you?
I'll go get Xia Xue
and see if she believes what you say.
Lin Hua!
Are you going to talk?
The camcorder we took up
the mountain that day
was picked up by Li Dong.
What did it record?
What does he want?
Don't worry about it.
I've already handled it.
Borrowed from loan sharks to fix it?
This has nothing to do with you.
Stay out of it.
Remember,
Xia Xue must never know.
[Flower Shop]
Lu Ming.
How did you get hurt?
It's nothing.
I just got into a fight.
Let's go for a walk.
♪ The sunset lingers on my left cheek ♪
♪ Like words that stop
just short of being said ♪
♪ I hide all my thoughts
in the old phone ♪
When we first came back,
we wanted to swim to the other shore,
♪ And say, as if it's nothing,
"How have you been lately?" ♪
but before long,
a wave pushed us back.
Thinking about it now,
we were like
♪ Just a "long time no see" ♪
a boat without sails on this sea.
We couldn't have reached the shore.
♪ After all these years ♪
We can do it.
♪ The platform lights
flicker on and fade ♪
I've never been superstitious,
♪ When I open my eyes again,
you're already gone ♪
but after all that's happened,
I feel like I'm just
someone who's very...
♪ Goodbye or never again ♪
What are you thinking?
I'm serious.
♪ We'll meet again someday ♪
♪ Whether I hope for it or not ♪
Do you trust me?
♪ I'll face it calmly all the same ♪
♪ You ask me where I'm going next time ♪
Xia Xue.
Actually, I had
prepared a proposal speech.
But now I feel those words
aren't important anymore.
In my life,
I've made many decisions.
But never one like today
that made me question myself repeatedly.
Because you're the best girl in the world.
You deserve to have
all the good things in this world.
Let me protect you for life.
Marry me, Xia Xue.
[Half a month later]
Xia Xue.
I made you some soup.
Drink it while it's hot.
What's wrong?
I'm a little tired.
Come on, taste it while it's hot.
How is it?
My mom told me to make sure
I watch you drink it.
Also,
I still have some things to do.
Once I'm done,
we can buy tickets back to school.
Take your time drinking it.